Rick Farouni | Curriculum Vitae

Department of Psychology, The Ohio State University

rfarouni@gmail.com • http://rfarouni.github.io/

I am currently a doctoral candidate in quantitative psychology at the Ohio State University. I hold a master's degree in mathematical statistics. I have excellent skills in scientific computing and a strong background in machine learning, multivariate statistics, and Bayesian statistics. My research is focused on latent variable modelling and the statistical analysis of fMRI neuroimaging data. I am passionate about the open access movement in education, research, and academia and I am dedicated to rigorous science in the public interest.

Education

Academic Qualifications.

The Ohio State UniversityOhio, USAPhD in Quantitative Psychology2012–PresentAdvisor: Professor Robert Cudeck

The Ohio State University

Master of Science in Statistics [GPA 3.80/4]

The Ohio State University

Master's Degree in Quantitative Psychology

Ohio, USA
2012-2014

Thesis Project: 'Latent Variable Modelling of Categorical Item Responses in a Hierarchical Bayesian Framework'

Bachelor's Degree in Psychology with High Distinction [GPA 3.93/4]

Pennsylvania, USA 2011-2012

Seattle

Course Projects....

- Multivariate Statistics (STAT 7560): 'Retinotopic Mapping of the Human Visual Cortex Using Independent Component Analysis'
- Advanced Computational Statistics (STAT 7730): 'Bayesian Analysis of Noisy Images Using Markov Random Fields'
- Statistical Consulting (STAT 6750): 'Modelling Categorical Perception of Speech Sounds using Beta Regression'

Conference Presentations

Joint Statistical Meetings

The Pennsylvania State University

0	Poster Title: Across-Subject Predictive Modeling of fMRI BOLD Responses to Faces	2015
<u> </u>	Awards and Fellowships	
0	Graduate Student Conference Presentation Award The Ohio State University	2015
0	The Center for Cognitive and Brain Sciences Summer Graduate Fellowship The Ohio State University	2015
	Project Proposal : 'Decoding the Pixels of the Face Image from the Voxels of fMRI BOLD Activity Patterns'	
0	The Social and Behavioral Sciences Summer Fellowship The Ohio State University	2014
0	University Fellowship The Ohio State University	2012

Experience

Teaching Experience.

Graduate Teaching Associate
The Ohio State University
Teaching Assistant for Psychology 2220: Data Analysis in Psychology

Test Preparation Instructor
Instructor of the Graduate Management Admission Test (GMAT)

Teacher of English as a Foreign Language
Teacher of General and Academic English

Ohio, USA
2013—present
Moscow, Russia
2009-2012

Moscow, Russia
2001-2009

Journal Review Service.....

Psychometrika

Ad Hoc Reviewer

Psychological Methods

Ad Hoc Reviewer

2015

Technical Skill Set

- Numerical and Statistical Programming: Proficient in and comfortable transitioning between R, Python, Julia, and Matlab depending on computing goals. Strong command of probabilistic programming languages such as Stan and Venture (to a lesser extent).
- Computing Tools and Web Technologies: Experience with a variety of technologies such as LaTeX , Linux OS, Git. Basic knowledge in website development tools such as HTML, CSS, and Jekyll.
- Big Data and High-Performance Computing: Good knowledge of running numerical analyses on the Ohio Supercomputer Center's main clusters. Basic familiarity with distributed cluster computing using the Spark platform.
- Deep Learning Software: Experienced in training deep learning models on GPUs using Caffe, MXNet, and Neon frameworks.
- Neuroimaging Analysis Software: Experienced in working with Nipype, PyMVPA, FreeSurfer, Pycortex, SPM and FSL.
- **Bioinformatics Software:** Experienced in analysing gene expression data and next-generation sequencing data (i.e. RNA-seq) using R's Bioconductor set of tools. MOOC Classes taken:
 - HarvardX: PH525.4x Data Analysis for Life Sciences 4: High-Dimensional Data Analysis
 HarvardX: PH525.5x Data Analysis for Life Sciences 5: Introduction to Bioconductor
 - HarvardX: PH525.5x Data Analysis for Life Sciences 5: Introduction to Bioconductor
 HarvardX: PH525.6x Data Analysis for Life Sciences 6: High-performance Computing
 - HarvardX: PH525.6x Data Analysis for Life Sciences 6: High-performance Computing for Reproducible Genomics (enrolled)

Personal Details

- Country of Previous Residence: Russia (12 years)
 Marital Status: Married
- Marital Status: Married
 Interests and Hobbies: Evolutionary Biology, World Cuisines, Experimental Music
- Languages Spoken: English, Arabic, Russian, Spanish (limited)